Man Searching for Immortality/Woman Searching for Eternity
is a drama film directed by Bill Viola.
Two naked, life-sized figures, each around 70 years old, track torches across
their aging epidermises as if rooting out the pattern of their pasts.
The skin itself becomes a metaphor for lived experience
and the prospect of its termination.
Performer, played by Luis Accinelli.
Performer, played by Penny Safranek.
Wings of Desire (German: Der Himmel über Berlin,
pronounced [deːɐ̯ ˈhɪml̩ ˈʔyːbɐ bɛɐ̯ˈliːn] ; lit.
'The Heaven/Sky over Berlin') is a 1987 romantic fantasy film written by Wim
Wenders, Peter Handke and Richard Reitinger, and directed by Wenders.
The film is about invisible, immortal angels who populate Berlin and listen to
the thoughts of its human inhabitants, comforting the distressed.
Even though the city is densely populated, many of the people
are isolated or estranged from their loved ones.
One of the angels, played by Bruno Ganz, falls in love with a
beautiful, lonely trapeze artist, played by Solveig Dommartin.
The angel chooses to become mortal so that he can experience human sensory pleasures, ranging from enjoying
food to touching a loved one, and so that he can discover human love with the trapeze artist.
Inspired by art depicting angels visible around West Berlin, at the time encircled by the Berlin Wall, Wenders and author Peter
Handke conceived of the story and continued to develop the screenplay throughout the French and German co-production.
The film was shot by Henri Alekan in both colour and black-and-white, the
latter being used to represent the world as seen by the angels.
The cast includes Otto Sander, Curt Bois and Peter Falk.
For Wings of Desire, Wenders won awards for Best Director at both
the Cannes Film Festival and European Film Awards.
The film was a critical and financial success, and academics have interpreted it as a statement of the importance of
cinema, libraries, the circus, or German unity, containing New Age, religious, secular or other themes.
It was followed by a sequel, Faraway, So Close!, released in 1993.
City of Angels, a U.S.
remake, was released in 1998.
In 1990, numerous critics named Wings of Desire as
one of the best films of the 1980s.